<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Book of Daniel</title>
    <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Book of Daniel</description>
    <image>
      <title>Book of Daniel</title>
      <url>https://bookofdaniel.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.134.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 05:57:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bookofdaniel.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Passing CKAD After Your CKA</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 05:57:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of Reddit users say that CKAD is easier than CKA. Personally, I agree—it does feel lighter if you attempt CKAD after completing CKA. The CKAD focuses more on scheduling tasks, while CKA involves administration of clusters. So, in CKAD, it&amp;rsquo;s more about speed and being quick with your typing to finish all the questions in time. 🏃‍♂️🕒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-study-approach&#34;&gt;My Study Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/&#34;&gt;After passing the CKA two weeks earlier&lt;/a&gt;, I had a pretty good idea of what the exam interface and questions would be like. I compared the CKA and CKAD certifications to see what additional topics I needed to cover for CKAD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How My 15-Month-Old Baby Helped Me Pass the CKA Exam</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 16:25:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last November, I scheduled my CKA exam, but guess what? I kept putting it off for months. Every time I thought about studying Kubernetes, it felt like I was facing an enormous mountain I wasn’t ready to climb. Life got busy, I lost motivation, and the exam remained on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July, I bought the KodeKloud CKA course, thinking it would push me to start studying. I studied a little, then stopped, and this cycle went on for weeks. Kubernetes seemed too big and complex to handle, and I didn’t know where to begin. And then, life happened—my father was hospitalized, and I had even less drive to study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSL Pinning: Safeguarding Your App Against Man-in-the-Middle Attacks</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/ssl-pinning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 17:13:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/ssl-pinning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, security researchers discovered a critical vulnerability in the HSBC mobile banking app for iOS. The app was found to be susceptible to man-in-the-middle (MITM) attacks, allowing attackers to intercept and manipulate sensitive financial information. The root of the problem? The absence of SSL pinning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without SSL pinning, the app was vulnerable to accepting any SSL certificate, even a forged one, which enabled attackers to eavesdrop on the communication between the app and HSBC&amp;rsquo;s servers. This security flaw put users&amp;rsquo; banking information at risk and highlighted a significant gap in the app&amp;rsquo;s security framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Explained: The Post Office of Modern Data Streaming</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kafka-explained-the-post-office-of-modern-data-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 13:47:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kafka-explained-the-post-office-of-modern-data-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joshua had been waiting anxiously for weeks. As an aspiring clerk, he knew that the government official&amp;rsquo;s appointment order could arrive any day. This appointment was crucial—it would determine his future and career. Every morning, Joshua checked his local post office, hoping that today would be the day the letter arrived, confirming his new position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, Joshua’s experience mirrors how Kafka, a powerful distributed streaming platform, manages and delivers data. Just like how Joshua relies on the postal system to receive his appointment letter, modern data systems depend on Kafka to ensure that critical information reaches its intended recipients quickly and reliably.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Self-Signed Certificate for IIS and Host a Website</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-create-self-signed-certificate-for-iis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 16:03:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-create-self-signed-certificate-for-iis/</guid>
      <description>Create a self-signed certificate for your development site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why YAML and How to Ace It?</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-yaml-and-how-to-ace-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 21:15:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-yaml-and-how-to-ace-it/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered why on earth YAML was invented? I’ve been there—it can feel tough with all the indentation rules and quirks! If you’re feeling the same way, this blog post is for you!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Public Key Infrastructure and TLS Certificates</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/understanding-public-key-infrastructure-and-tls-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 16:31:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/understanding-public-key-infrastructure-and-tls-certificates/</guid>
      <description>How does your information securely transfer through internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Am Wearing Same Outfit Everyday</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-am-wearing-same-outfit-everyday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:07:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-am-wearing-same-outfit-everyday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Minimalism is not about having less. It&amp;rsquo;s about making room for more of what matters.&amp;rdquo; - Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first explored minimalism, I was struck by a pattern: many minimalists, myself included, often opt for a simple, repeatable outfit, such as a black t-shirt. Initially, this seemed almost like a uniform. But diving deeper into minimalism, I understood the profound reasons behind this choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-understanding-minimalism&#34;&gt;🕵️‍♂️ Understanding Minimalism:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is more than a fashion statement; it&amp;rsquo;s a mindset that encourages us to find beauty and satisfaction in simplicity. It&amp;rsquo;s about stripping away the non-essential to make room for what truly adds value to our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unstoppable Framework: A Step-by-Step Guide to Achieving Your Goals</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:06:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all aspire to be better, stronger, smarter, and healthier, yet many struggle to stick with their goals. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a practical framework that addresses this common issue, allowing you to effortlessly surpass your goals. This system has been successfully used to develop the discipline needed to hold a 15-minute plank every day. Join me on this journey, and let&amp;rsquo;s unlock your raw power together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-action-oriented-goals&#34;&gt;Step 1: Action-Oriented Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of setting vague and impractical goals, focus on specific actions within a defined time frame. For instance, rather than aiming to lose 20 pounds, set a goal to complete 10,000 push-ups by the end of the year. Break down the goal into actionable steps, visualize each step, and establish a non-negotiable daily minimum to make progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Productivity System: Get Things Done Effortlessly! 🚀</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:02:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the high-speed hustle of modern professional life, we often find ourselves chasing time, trying to grasp every fleeting minute. Productivity isn&amp;rsquo;t just a buzzword; it&amp;rsquo;s a lifeline that keeps us afloat in a sea of deadlines, meetings, and endless tasks. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a busy professional always on the lookout for the best way to streamline your day, you know that most productivity systems seem to add more to our plates rather than taking off the load.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reclaiming Our Digital Space: The Rise of NOSTR and the Renaissance of Social Media 💪🏻</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:00:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The early days of the internet were marked by a sense of freedom and innovation. Platforms like Twitter, founded by Jack Dorsey and others, were initially open-source ecosystems where developers could contribute, leading to features like hashtags and trending topics. This era was characterized by decentralized protocols, like email, allowing for diverse applications and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as platforms like Facebook, Twitter, and Google grew, they started organizing this vast information, turning social media into centralized repositories. This shift was efficient but led to the accumulation of power in the hands of a few companies, creating &amp;lsquo;walled gardens&amp;rsquo; where user data became a commodity for advertising revenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Batchology Handbook</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-batchology-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:59:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-batchology-handbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever wondered how to make your computer tasks faster and more efficient, you&amp;rsquo;re in the right place. This blog post is all about Batch scripting - a simple yet powerful way to automate tasks in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to programming or have some experience, &amp;ldquo;The Batchology Handbook&amp;rdquo; is designed to be easy to follow and understand. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the basics, like setting up your workspace, and gradually move into more exciting stuff, like automating file management and using cool commands you might not know about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Minute Death Journal Method</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-5-minute-death-journal-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:57:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-5-minute-death-journal-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the hustle and bustle of our daily lives, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to let moments slip by without much thought. The idea of journaling, while appealing in theory, often feels daunting in practice. After a long day, the last thing many of us want to do is reflect on our experiences and plan for the next. But what if I told you there&amp;rsquo;s a way to reap the benefits of journaling in just five minutes a day? Enter the 5-Minute Death Journal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Port Not Available</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/port-not-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:56:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/port-not-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, you read that right.&lt;/strong&gt; The port you’re trying to use is already occupied by another application. If you’re a system or network administrator, you’ve likely encountered this frustrating message more times than you care to remember. It’s challenging to pinpoint which application is hogging the port (though it’s not as hard as it seems, as I’ll show you 😉). These ghost messages can leave you in quite a pickle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Your Bed Summary</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/make-your-bed-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:55:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/make-your-bed-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture it: your bed, a chaotic landscape of tangled limbs and rogue pillows, mirroring the state of your life. Enter &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_H._McRaven&#34;&gt;Admiral William McRaven&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Make-Your-Bed-William-McRaven/dp/0718188861&#34;&gt;Make Your Bed&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a book that&amp;rsquo;s anything but your average fluff-and-fold self-help manual. Think less feng shui, more forging a battle cry in the crucible of Navy SEAL training. This ain&amp;rsquo;t about smoothing out your duvet; it&amp;rsquo;s about scaling metaphorical Mount Everest, one messy pillowcase at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned From a Former WhatsApp Engineer</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:54:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent YouTube video, a former WhatsApp engineer shared his insights on success in the tech industry and the key lessons he learned during his time at the company. Here are the main takeaways from his experience, formatted with lists and paragraphs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Key Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence and Likability&lt;/strong&gt;: Influence in the tech industry is about being likable and credible. People who are dependable and pleasant to work with are more likely to be sought after for new opportunities and promotions. Focus on building a strong reputation by being a good team player and delivering results. 👍&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Architecture Explained the Ship Analogy of KodeKloud</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kubernetes-architecture-explained-the-ship-analogy-of-kodekloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:52:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kubernetes-architecture-explained-the-ship-analogy-of-kodekloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our exploration of Kubernetes architecture! Kubernetes, often abbreviated as K8s, is a powerful tool designed to manage containerized applications in a scalable and automated fashion. This blog post aims to provide a high-level understanding of Kubernetes architecture using an analogy of ships, which simplifies the complex interplay between its components. Special thanks to KodeKloud for their insightful lecture, which inspired this overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-kubernetes-cluster-ships-at-sea&#34;&gt;The Kubernetes Cluster: Ships at Sea&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, a Kubernetes cluster comprises two types of nodes: worker nodes and master nodes. To understand their roles, let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a fleet of ships:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Principles of Any Cloud Environments</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/key-principles-of-any-cloud-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:51:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/key-principles-of-any-cloud-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Original Post : &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/application-development/5-principles-for-cloud-native-architecture-what-it-is-and-how-to-master-it&#34;&gt;https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/application-development/5-principles-for-cloud-native-architecture-what-it-is-and-how-to-master-it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the dynamic world of cloud computing, the term &amp;lsquo;cloud-native architecture&amp;rsquo; is often synonymous with innovation and efficiency. This article, inspired by a Google Cloud blog post, expands the concept to encompass universal principles applicable across all cloud platforms, be it Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud Platform (GCP). 🌦️🏗️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;understanding-cloud-native-architecture&#34;&gt;Understanding Cloud-Native Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud-native architecture is about leveraging the unique capabilities of cloud environments. It goes beyond mere migration to the cloud; it&amp;rsquo;s about optimizing applications to thrive in this dynamic ecosystem. 🌩️💡&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue Faced on WSFC Configuration for SQL Server AlwaysOn Setup</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/issue-faced-on-wsfc-configuration-for-sql-server-alwayson-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:51:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/issue-faced-on-wsfc-configuration-for-sql-server-alwayson-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of navigating through a wide array of technical landscapes. Yet, the recent endeavor of configuring a Windows Server Failover Cluster (WSFC) for SQL Server AlwaysOn presented a learning curve that was both steep and enriching. In this piece, I hope to share my experiences, the challenges encountered, and the lessons learned, with a spirit of humility and the intention of contributing to our collective knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Zoho Desk and Grafana</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:47:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been a part of a hardworking team that, despite their efforts, ends up shouldering blame? If yes, our situation in operations might resonate with you. On any given day, our Zoho Desk is inundated with approximately 300 tickets, each falling under various classifications and priorities. Many of these tickets are complex and time-consuming to resolve, causing them to carry over to the next day and become overdue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Kafka and Kafka Connect on Seperate Servers</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/installing-kafka-and-kafka-connect-on-seperate-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:46:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/installing-kafka-and-kafka-connect-on-seperate-servers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installing Kafka and Kafka Connect on separate servers allows for better resource management, especially in production environments where Kafka brokers and Connectors may need dedicated hardware. This guide will walk you through the steps to set up Kafka and Kafka Connect on separate Linux servers, using Ubuntu 24.04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two Linux machines&lt;/strong&gt; (Ubuntu 24.04)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inbound ports opened&lt;/strong&gt; on both servers:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kafka broker ports: 9092, 9093&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kafka Connect REST port: 8083&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java 11 (OpenJDK)&lt;/strong&gt; installed on both servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-set-up-kafka-on-the-first-server&#34;&gt;Step 1: Set Up Kafka on the First Server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set the hostname&lt;/strong&gt; for the Kafka server:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Supercharge Your Focus a Revolutionary Approach</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-supercharge-your-focus-a-revolutionar-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:45:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-supercharge-your-focus-a-revolutionar-approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow knowledge seekers! 🚀 Recently, I stumbled upon an incredibly inspiring YouTube video that reshaped my entire approach to focus and productivity. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll distill the essence of this video into a cool, easily digestible guide. Trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s not your typical &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo; list; it&amp;rsquo;s a game-changer! (P.S. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Pe-iBysIb7o&#34;&gt;original video&lt;/a&gt; here for the full experience!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-create-your-sacred-space-&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Create Your Sacred Space&lt;/strong&gt; 🌌&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to designate a &amp;ldquo;Sacred Space&amp;rdquo; - a special area used solely for studying or working. Imagine it as a holy box where productivity reigns supreme. Once you enter this space, work begins - no exceptions! This approach mirrors insomnia research, teaching you to associate certain places with specific activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Setup Kubernetes in Azure Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-setup-kubernetes-in-azure-virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:44:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-setup-kubernetes-in-azure-virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the hard way of installing Kubernetes in Azure Virtual Machines. The instructions will be moreover same for On-prem. For many developers, using managed Kubernetes services like GKE, EKS, or AKS can be convenient, but they often abstract away the intricate details of how a cluster operates under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;NODES&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;IP&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;HOSTNAME&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;MACHINE TYPE&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;OPERATING SYSTEM&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;master&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;172.16.39.14&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;k8s-master.local&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Standard B2ms&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 24.04&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;k8s-worker1&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;172.16.39.23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;k8s-worker1.local&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Standard B4ms&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 24.04&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;provisioning-the-servers-in-azure&#34;&gt;Provisioning the Servers in Azure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provision two Linux virtual machines (VMs) in Azure with the specified details, you can use the Azure CLI (az) to achieve this. Here’s how you can provision both machines using az vm create commands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Programmers Can Become 10X More Effective</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-programmers-can-become-10x-more-effective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:43:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-programmers-can-become-10x-more-effective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where technology is ever-evolving, programmers are constantly seeking ways to enhance their skills and productivity. A treasure trove of wisdom that is often overlooked in the tech community is Stephen Covey&amp;rsquo;s iconic book, &amp;ldquo;7 Habits of Highly Effective People.&amp;rdquo; Sahil, a YouTuber, sheds light on how this book can be a game-changer for programmers aspiring to amplify their effectiveness tenfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-the-essence-of-proactivity-in-programming&#34;&gt;1. The Essence of Proactivity in Programming&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covey distinguishes between reactive and proactive individuals, drawing a parallel with programmers. Reactive programmers might wait for a life-changing tutorial or a list of interview questions to boost their career. In contrast, proactive programmers take ownership of their growth. They invest time in understanding the fundamentals, practicing coding, and building projects. This mindset shift from dependency to self-reliance is crucial for any programmer aiming for excellence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Started a YouTube Channel and Got 100K Subscribers in 6 Months (Even Though I Got Copyright Strikes)</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:35:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 lockdown, people had differing views: some felt it could be the end, while others saw it as an opportunity to start something new. One common thread was that everyone was glued to their smartphones. YouTube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/trends/articles/covid-impact/&#34;&gt;trends during the pandemic&lt;/a&gt; showed skyrocketing watch times since everyone was either watching videos or sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube Shorts started gaining more traction over time, particularly those related to motivation. Everyone needed motivation because those were the tough times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Does TLS Works Under the Hood</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-does-tls-works-under-the-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:34:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-does-tls-works-under-the-hood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the cold winter of 1944, Germany’s once-unbreakable &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enigma_machine&#34;&gt;Enigma&lt;/a&gt; code had been compromised by the Allies. With every intercepted message, their plans were at risk of exposure, and entire operations could be jeopardized. In response, German High Command devised a new, unbreakable system of communication. They called it &lt;strong&gt;Operation Valkyrie&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t just another machine like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enigma_machine&#34;&gt;Enigma&lt;/a&gt;; this was a new system that couldn’t be cracked, even if the messages were intercepted. Colonel Franz Richter, a seasoned officer in charge of communications, knew that their most sensitive military orders would need to be protected more securely than ever. He gathered his top commanders, including Major Klaus Weber, to unveil the system that could change the course of the war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Beginners Guide to Vim Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/a-beginners-guide-to-vim-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:31:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/a-beginners-guide-to-vim-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vim is a highly configurable text editor used in programming. It&amp;rsquo;s known for its efficiency, enabling users to navigate and edit documents with minimal use of the mouse. This blog post will introduce you to the most important Vim shortcuts and commands, making your coding journey smoother and more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-vim-modes&#34;&gt;Understanding Vim Modes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the commands, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand Vim&amp;rsquo;s modes. Vim operates in several modes, each with a specific purpose:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Ways to Stay Fit While Sitting at Home</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/15-ways-to-stay-fit-while-sitting-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:17:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/15-ways-to-stay-fit-while-sitting-at-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our current era of remote work and virtual learning, prioritizing physical and mental fitness is more crucial than ever. Luckily, there are numerous strategies you can incorporate into your daily routine without stepping outside your home. The following 15 ways, inspired by the insightful content from a YouTube video by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/FKNRNY5ji_M?si=ueCpV5g2vEtG5bjS&#34;&gt;Warikoo&lt;/a&gt;, will guide you towards a healthier and more balanced lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-fitness&#34;&gt;Basic Fitness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sit Straight&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintain a good posture while working or studying. Use a memory foam pillow or a similar support to keep your back straight and avoid slouching.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
