<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel</title>
    <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 22:45:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://bookofdaniel.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>How I Started a YouTube Channel and Got 100K Subscribers in 6 Months (Even Though I Got Copyright Strikes)</title>
        <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 08:54:22 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/</guid>
        <description>🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/ -&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 lockdown, people had differing views: some felt it could be the end, while others saw it as an opportunity to start something new. One common thread was that everyone was glued to their smartphones. YouTube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/trends/articles/covid-impact/&#34;&gt;trends during the pandemic&lt;/a&gt; showed skyrocketing watch times since everyone was either watching videos or sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube Shorts started gaining more traction over time, particularly those related to motivation. Everyone needed motivation because those were the tough times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;seizing-the-moment-&#34;&gt;Seizing the Moment ⏱️&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was late to join the motivation genre. In June 2022, I realized the potential of starting a motivational channel. Compared to the other channels, like &amp;lsquo;Day in the Life&amp;rsquo;, educational, or travel channels, it&amp;rsquo;s relatively simple. You just cut clips from long-form videos of other channels into shorts of less than 30 or 60 seconds with copyright-free music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started multiple motivational channels like learnwithniel and musetales. Some garnered a few views in the first month due to the infamous YouTube algorithm push. After that, the views dwindled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve long been a fan of Jay Shetty and a regular viewer of his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@JayShettyPodcast.&#34;&gt;Jay Shetty Podcast channel&lt;/a&gt;. In December 2022, I noticed there were no fan channels for Jay Shetty, so I started one called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@jayshettyshorts&#34;&gt;Jay Shetty Shorts&lt;/a&gt; 😉.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Jay Shetty is a popular motivational speaker, the channel was a hit. It attracted a lot of attention from both haters and supporters, which helped increase views and comments 😊.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img title=&#34;Jay Shetty Fan Channel&#34; alt=&#34;Jay Shetty Fan Channel&#34; src=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/images/Jay Shetty Fan Channel.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-grind-of-consistency-&#34;&gt;The Grind of Consistency 💪🏻&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting the YouTube channel, I thought it was easy money—people post videos and earn millions, like a money-printing machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I realized that being a YouTuber is not easy! It&amp;rsquo;s a commitment to subscribers. If you&amp;rsquo;re consistent, the YouTube Algorithm will promote your videos, leading to more views. I committed to posting 2 clips + 2 shorts daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was difficult because I was not naturally consistent. After starting this channel, I committed myself to editing videos daily. There were many sleepless nights, as I had to balance this with my day job. But let me tell you, it was worth it, and I experienced the power of consistency in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Success isn&amp;rsquo;t always about greatness. It&amp;rsquo;s about consistency. Consistent hard work leads to success. Greatness will come.&amp;rdquo; - Dwayne Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;beyond-subscribers-and-likes-&#34;&gt;Beyond Subscribers and Likes 👍🏻&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On YouTube, having a large number of subscribers doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean higher earnings; it&amp;rsquo;s all about the views. If you have more views, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn more and gain subscribers as a by-product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comments from Jay Shetty&amp;rsquo;s fans were one of my motivations for this channel. It was inspiring to see how supporters took the content to heart and how it inspired them to express love and inspire others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But remember, if you&amp;rsquo;re solely focused on subscriber count, comments, and likes, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to continue the journey of being a YouTuber. Do good work and commit to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earning for your hard work is also important since you&amp;rsquo;re investing a lot of effort and precious time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time is what we want most, but what we use worst.&amp;rdquo; - William Penn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;monetization-and-google-adsense-&#34;&gt;Monetization and Google AdSense 💰&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube isn&amp;rsquo;t the money printing machine I once thought it was. Your channel only starts earning after reaching certain thresholds: 1000 Subscribers (now 500), 4000 watch hours (now 3000), and for Shorts, 3 million valid public shorts views in 90 days. These thresholds are there to ensure you&amp;rsquo;re consistent and to see if it&amp;rsquo;s worth betting on you for Google AdSense revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the grace of God, I started earning within 1.5 months. The revenue isn&amp;rsquo;t the same for every channel; it depends on the content and the ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/shorts/uG64TZWbQSc&#34;&gt;Shorts video&lt;/a&gt;  featuring Jay Shetty and Drew Barrymore helped me surpass the YouTube revenue threshold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes all you need is a single shot to turn your hard work into a dream ✨; keep digging ⛏️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-milestone-100k-subscribers--the-silver-play-button-&#34;&gt;The Milestone: 100K Subscribers &amp;amp; The Silver Play Button 🏆&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After six months of sleepless nights and consistent hard work, the channel reached 100K subscribers ✨.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img title=&#34;YouTube channel views&#34; alt=&#34;YouTube channel views for 2023&#34; src=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/images/YouTube Views.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this number of subscribers mean something? Yes, in terms of hard work and consistency it&amp;rsquo;s a reward, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you&amp;rsquo;re superior to anyone else; it humbles you to thank every subscriber, hater, and supporter for engaging with the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about three weeks to receive the YouTube Silver Play Button after reaching 100K subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding that award for the first time felt good. I thanked Almighty God for it and, like a typical human being, shared the news on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my colleagues and friends were surprised because only a few knew that I owned a YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After posting on social media, I put the award back in its box and stored it away. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to frame it and hang it on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;copyright-strike-&#34;&gt;Copyright Strike ⚡️&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I had posted over 1000 videos and amassed 100K+ subscribers, I began receiving copyright strikes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.superbam.com/&#34;&gt;SuperBam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had anticipated this for a long time. 😊 Although it was a fan channel, the content was still from the Jay Shetty Podcast Channel. The copyright strike was legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of the strike was such that I could continue posting videos but was prohibited from earning any revenue from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-end&#34;&gt;The End&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have stopped posting videos as we are receiving copyright strikes ⚡️. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so many things over these months and am thankful to Jay Shetty for pushing me to exceed my own limits regarding consistency. Editing his 1000+ videos has taught me about his commitment to his purpose and his consistency in posting weekly without fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are planning to start a YouTube channel, I hope this will serve as motivation for you. Consistency is the key in every trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The best time to start a YouTube channel was yesterday.&amp;rdquo; - Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/ - 2023</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Push your team to be Good to Great: Integration of Zoho Desk and Grafana</title>
        <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 17:40:05 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/</guid>
        <description>🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/ -&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been a part of a hardworking team that, despite their efforts, ends up shouldering blame? If yes, our situation in operations might resonate with you. On any given day, our Zoho Desk is inundated with approximately 300 tickets, each falling under various classifications and priorities. Many of these tickets are complex and time-consuming to resolve, causing them to carry over to the next day and become overdue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge we face is the lack of visibility into critical metrics. Questions like the total number of tickets created, the various classifications in use, the resource who close the most tickets, and pending tickets are difficult to answer definitively. Convincing others about the work overload has proven to be quite a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Zoho Desk does offer predefined dashboards and customization options, our workflow relies heavily on custom fields. Additionally, the platform lacks real-time monitoring capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve followed along this far, you may find yourself in a similar scenario or be seeking solutions for building real-time monitoring functionality within Zoho Desk. Keep reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a team, we set out to tackle these challenges head-on, with the ultimate goal of maximizing throughput and efficiency to ensure customer satisfaction. Here are the key challenges we identified on our team board:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Large Team Management:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
With a growing client base, our team size has expanded proportionally. Managing a larger team is becoming increasingly challenging without access to key metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Ticket Assignment Automation:&lt;/strong&gt;
Currently, our ticket assignment process involves agents or team members manually assigning tickets from a common email account. Some agents assign tickets to themselves, while others choose to assign them to the next team member. This variation in assignment might be due to differences in ticket complexity, with some opting for the low-hanging fruit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Timely Escalation:&lt;/strong&gt;
To maintain SLA compliance, we required a solution which will escalate the tickets to a manager when there is breach in a predefined time threshold (e.g., x minutes/hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Email Tickets with Mandatory Fields:&lt;/strong&gt;
Zoho Desk offers a convenient feature that allows users to raise tickets via email. However, this feature creates tickets without mandatory fields, such as client or environment name. This calls for communicating the team over and over again resulting in time consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Real-Time Monitoring &amp;amp; Scoreboard:&lt;/strong&gt;
The absence of a real-time dashboard has caused inefficiencies in tracking productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improving Daily work is even more important than doing daily work.&lt;/strong&gt;  - The Phoenix Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have slept on these challenges for a day and explored the Zoho documentation along with some Google search. It seemed like I could solve some of these issues using zoho&amp;rsquo;s features, while others might require development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Large Team Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Proposed to split the team into multiple pods or pools. So that it can be managed by a senior / lead with minimal members and work can be monitored efficiently. &lt;br&gt; Pool segregation will be based on the number of clients.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Ticket Assignment Automation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Since the team is arranged into multiple pools, based on the client hierarchy, whenever a ticket is raised for the specific client it should be allocated directly to the respecitve pool. Then the pool lead / member can assign and work accordingly. &lt;br&gt; To Automate this process Zoho Desk provides a feature called &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.zoho.com/portal/en/kb/desk/automation/assignment-rules-notification/articles/creating-ticket-assignment-rules&#34;&gt;Direct Assignment&lt;/a&gt;. Create an assignment rule with client name and select respective pool account. Viola! The ticket will be assigned automatically on creation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Timely Escalation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Zoho provides a feature called &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.zoho.com/portal/en/kb/desk/automation/escalate-sla/articles/creating-and-using-slas&#34;&gt;SLAs&lt;/a&gt; escalation. If an escalation occurs within x minutes it will be escalated to 2 levels. We chose to adopt it, so that the breached ticket will be esclated to the respective lead / manager of the pool within 30 mins.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Email Ticket with mandatory fields&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;We created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.zoho.com/portal/en/kb/desk/activities/articles/working-with-tasks-zoho-desk#Creating_Tasks&#34;&gt;Zoho Task&lt;/a&gt; to close the email ticket with an automated reply to fill the mandatory fields. So the tickets in which the mandatory fields are not filled will be closed automatically.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-time-monitoring--scoreboard&#34;&gt;Real-Time Monitoring &amp;amp; Scoreboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoho analytics with additional license offers Dashboard experience but I needed something more interesting like a real-time dashboard to proactively act on tickets which does not require additional license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I came up with a solution which is powered by Grafana Dashboard and projected it on a monitor. For that, I used zoho web hook, instead of polling ticket meta details from Zoho desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Webhook listener is developed using a simple java script. The json payload recieved will be deserialized and stored in a relational database like SQL Server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I created a Grafana Dashboard to pull the details from the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;architecture-diagram&#34;&gt;Architecture Diagram&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img title=&#34;Zoho Real-Time Grafana Dashbord&#34; alt=&#34;Zoho Real-Time Dashboard Solution&#34; src=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/images/Zoho Desk Real Time Monitoring.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-results&#34;&gt;Final Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img title=&#34;Zoho Real-Time Grafana Dashbord&#34; alt=&#34;Zoho Real-Time Dashboard Solution on TV&#34; src=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/images/Zoho Desk Real Time Monitoring on TV.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By incorporating real-time monitoring for Zoho tickets, my team&amp;rsquo;s productivity and efficiency increased tenfold. This enhancement not only bolstered accountability but also motivated everyone to aim higher and soar!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A great team doesn’t mean that they had the smartest people. What made those teams great is that everyone trusted one another. It can be a powerful thing when that magic dynamic exists.&lt;/strong&gt; - The Phoenix Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/ - 2023</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 