<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on 🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel</title>
    <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/categories/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on 🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 22:24:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bookofdaniel.in/categories/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Programmers Can Become 10X More Effective by Applying the &#34;7 Habits of Highly Effective People&#34;</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-programmers-can-become-10x-more-effective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 22:24:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-programmers-can-become-10x-more-effective/</guid>
      <description>In a world where technology is ever-evolving, programmers are constantly seeking ways to enhance their skills and productivity. A treasure trove of wisdom that is often overlooked in the tech community is Stephen Covey&amp;rsquo;s iconic book, &amp;ldquo;7 Habits of Highly Effective People.&amp;rdquo; Sahil, a YouTuber, sheds light on how this book can be a game-changer for programmers aspiring to amplify their effectiveness tenfold.
1. The Essence of Proactivity in Programming Covey distinguishes between reactive and proactive individuals, drawing a parallel with programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues Faced During WSFC Configuration for SQL Server AlwaysOn Setup</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/issue-faced-on-wsfc-configuration-for-sql-server-alwayson-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 22:58:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/issue-faced-on-wsfc-configuration-for-sql-server-alwayson-setup/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of navigating through a wide array of technical landscapes. Yet, the recent endeavor of configuring a Windows Server Failover Cluster (WSFC) for SQL Server AlwaysOn presented a learning curve that was both steep and enriching. In this piece, I hope to share my experiences, the challenges encountered, and the lessons learned, with a spirit of humility and the intention of contributing to our collective knowledge base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unstoppable Framework: A Step-by-Step Guide to Achieving Your Goals</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 08:04:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</guid>
      <description>We all aspire to be better, stronger, smarter, and healthier, yet many struggle to stick with their goals. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a practical framework that addresses this common issue, allowing you to effortlessly surpass your goals. This system has been successfully used to develop the discipline needed to hold a 15-minute plank every day. Join me on this journey, and let&amp;rsquo;s unlock your raw power together.
Step 1: Action-Oriented Goals Instead of setting vague and impractical goals, focus on specific actions within a defined time frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from a Former WhatsApp Engineer: Influence, Passion, and Prioritization in the Tech Industry 🌟</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 09:19:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</guid>
      <description>In a recent YouTube video, a former WhatsApp engineer shared his insights on success in the tech industry and the key lessons he learned during his time at the company. Here are the main takeaways from his experience, formatted with lists and paragraphs:
Key Lessons Learned Influence and Likability: Influence in the tech industry is about being likable and credible. People who are dependable and pleasant to work with are more likely to be sought after for new opportunities and promotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 principles for cloud-native architecture: An Inspired Post 🔥</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/key-principles-of-any-cloud-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:49:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/key-principles-of-any-cloud-environments/</guid>
      <description>Original Post : https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/application-development/5-principles-for-cloud-native-architecture-what-it-is-and-how-to-master-it
In the dynamic world of cloud computing, the term &amp;lsquo;cloud-native architecture&amp;rsquo; is often synonymous with innovation and efficiency. This article, inspired by a Google Cloud blog post, expands the concept to encompass universal principles applicable across all cloud platforms, be it Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud Platform (GCP). 🌦️🏗️
Understanding Cloud-Native Architecture Cloud-native architecture is about leveraging the unique capabilities of cloud environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reclaiming Our Digital Space: The Rise of NOSTR and the Renaissance of Social Media 💪🏻</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 23:03:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</guid>
      <description>The early days of the internet were marked by a sense of freedom and innovation. Platforms like Twitter, founded by Jack Dorsey and others, were initially open-source ecosystems where developers could contribute, leading to features like hashtags and trending topics. This era was characterized by decentralized protocols, like email, allowing for diverse applications and innovation.
However, as platforms like Facebook, Twitter, and Google grew, they started organizing this vast information, turning social media into centralized repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Productivity System: Get Things Done Effortlessly! 🚀</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:59:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</guid>
      <description>In the high-speed hustle of modern professional life, we often find ourselves chasing time, trying to grasp every fleeting minute. Productivity isn&amp;rsquo;t just a buzzword; it&amp;rsquo;s a lifeline that keeps us afloat in a sea of deadlines, meetings, and endless tasks. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a busy professional always on the lookout for the best way to streamline your day, you know that most productivity systems seem to add more to our plates rather than taking off the load.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
