<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on 🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel</title>
    <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on 🧑🏻‍💻 Book Of Daniel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 12:53:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Port Not Available: 503 Server Unavailable</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/port-not-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 12:53:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/port-not-available/</guid>
      <description>Yes, you read that right. The port you’re trying to use is already occupied by another application. If you’re a system or network administrator, you’ve likely encountered this frustrating message more times than you care to remember. It’s challenging to pinpoint which application is hogging the port (though it’s not as hard as it seems, as I’ll show you 😉). These ghost messages can leave you in quite a pickle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Architecture Explained: the Ship Analogy of KodeKloud</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kubernetes-architecture-explained-the-ship-analogy-of-kodekloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 08:28:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kubernetes-architecture-explained-the-ship-analogy-of-kodekloud/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to our exploration of Kubernetes architecture! Kubernetes, often abbreviated as K8s, is a powerful tool designed to manage containerized applications in a scalable and automated fashion. This blog post aims to provide a high-level understanding of Kubernetes architecture using an analogy of ships, which simplifies the complex interplay between its components. Special thanks to KodeKloud for their insightful lecture, which inspired this overview.
The Kubernetes Cluster: Ships at Sea At its core, a Kubernetes cluster comprises two types of nodes: worker nodes and master nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Minute Death Journal Method</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-5-minute-death-journal-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 10:16:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-5-minute-death-journal-method/</guid>
      <description>In the hustle and bustle of our daily lives, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to let moments slip by without much thought. The idea of journaling, while appealing in theory, often feels daunting in practice. After a long day, the last thing many of us want to do is reflect on our experiences and plan for the next. But what if I told you there&amp;rsquo;s a way to reap the benefits of journaling in just five minutes a day?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Daily Plan for Success</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/a-daily-plan-for-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 14:44:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/a-daily-plan-for-success/</guid>
      <description>Are you struggling to stay focused and accomplish your goals amidst a sea of distractions? Do you find yourself procrastinating more often than not? If so, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Many of us face similar challenges in our daily lives, especially when working from home or in a busy environment. But fear not, because today I want to share with you a simple yet powerful daily plan inspired by insights from Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;Deep Work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Programmers Can Become 10X More Effective by Applying the &#34;7 Habits of Highly Effective People&#34;</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-programmers-can-become-10x-more-effective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 22:24:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-programmers-can-become-10x-more-effective/</guid>
      <description>In a world where technology is ever-evolving, programmers are constantly seeking ways to enhance their skills and productivity. A treasure trove of wisdom that is often overlooked in the tech community is Stephen Covey&amp;rsquo;s iconic book, &amp;ldquo;7 Habits of Highly Effective People.&amp;rdquo; Sahil, a YouTuber, sheds light on how this book can be a game-changer for programmers aspiring to amplify their effectiveness tenfold.
1. The Essence of Proactivity in Programming Covey distinguishes between reactive and proactive individuals, drawing a parallel with programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues Faced During WSFC Configuration for SQL Server AlwaysOn Setup</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/issue-faced-on-wsfc-configuration-for-sql-server-alwayson-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 22:58:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/issue-faced-on-wsfc-configuration-for-sql-server-alwayson-setup/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of navigating through a wide array of technical landscapes. Yet, the recent endeavor of configuring a Windows Server Failover Cluster (WSFC) for SQL Server AlwaysOn presented a learning curve that was both steep and enriching. In this piece, I hope to share my experiences, the challenges encountered, and the lessons learned, with a spirit of humility and the intention of contributing to our collective knowledge base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Batchology Handbook: Mastering the Art of Batch Scripting in Windows</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-batchology-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 22:45:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-batchology-handbook/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever wondered how to make your computer tasks faster and more efficient, you&amp;rsquo;re in the right place. This blog post is all about Batch scripting - a simple yet powerful way to automate tasks in Windows.
Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to programming or have some experience, &amp;ldquo;The Batchology Handbook&amp;rdquo; is designed to be easy to follow and understand. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the basics, like setting up your workspace, and gradually move into more exciting stuff, like automating file management and using cool commands you might not know about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unstoppable Framework: A Step-by-Step Guide to Achieving Your Goals</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 08:04:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</guid>
      <description>We all aspire to be better, stronger, smarter, and healthier, yet many struggle to stick with their goals. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a practical framework that addresses this common issue, allowing you to effortlessly surpass your goals. This system has been successfully used to develop the discipline needed to hold a 15-minute plank every day. Join me on this journey, and let&amp;rsquo;s unlock your raw power together.
Step 1: Action-Oriented Goals Instead of setting vague and impractical goals, focus on specific actions within a defined time frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from a Former WhatsApp Engineer: Influence, Passion, and Prioritization in the Tech Industry 🌟</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 09:19:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</guid>
      <description>In a recent YouTube video, a former WhatsApp engineer shared his insights on success in the tech industry and the key lessons he learned during his time at the company. Here are the main takeaways from his experience, formatted with lists and paragraphs:
Key Lessons Learned Influence and Likability: Influence in the tech industry is about being likable and credible. People who are dependable and pleasant to work with are more likely to be sought after for new opportunities and promotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Messy Sheets to Mountain Everest: Navigating Life with Lessons from a Navy SEAL</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/make-your-bed-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 16:26:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/make-your-bed-summary/</guid>
      <description>Picture it: your bed, a chaotic landscape of tangled limbs and rogue pillows, mirroring the state of your life. Enter Admiral William McRaven&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Make Your Bed,&amp;rdquo; a book that&amp;rsquo;s anything but your average fluff-and-fold self-help manual. Think less feng shui, more forging a battle cry in the crucible of Navy SEAL training. This ain&amp;rsquo;t about smoothing out your duvet; it&amp;rsquo;s about scaling metaphorical Mount Everest, one messy pillowcase at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Ways to Stay Fit While Sitting at Home</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/15-ways-to-stay-fit-while-sitting-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 16:12:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/15-ways-to-stay-fit-while-sitting-at-home/</guid>
      <description>In our current era of remote work and virtual learning, prioritizing physical and mental fitness is more crucial than ever. Luckily, there are numerous strategies you can incorporate into your daily routine without stepping outside your home. The following 15 ways, inspired by the insightful content from a YouTube video by Warikoo, will guide you towards a healthier and more balanced lifestyle.
Basic Fitness Sit Straight: Maintain a good posture while working or studying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beginners Guide to Vim Shortcuts</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/a-beginners-guide-to-vim-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 09:39:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/a-beginners-guide-to-vim-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Vim is a highly configurable text editor used in programming. It&amp;rsquo;s known for its efficiency, enabling users to navigate and edit documents with minimal use of the mouse. This blog post will introduce you to the most important Vim shortcuts and commands, making your coding journey smoother and more efficient.
Understanding Vim Modes Before we dive into the commands, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand Vim&amp;rsquo;s modes. Vim operates in several modes, each with a specific purpose:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 principles for cloud-native architecture: An Inspired Post 🔥</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/key-principles-of-any-cloud-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:49:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/key-principles-of-any-cloud-environments/</guid>
      <description>Original Post : https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/application-development/5-principles-for-cloud-native-architecture-what-it-is-and-how-to-master-it
In the dynamic world of cloud computing, the term &amp;lsquo;cloud-native architecture&amp;rsquo; is often synonymous with innovation and efficiency. This article, inspired by a Google Cloud blog post, expands the concept to encompass universal principles applicable across all cloud platforms, be it Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, or Google Cloud Platform (GCP). 🌦️🏗️
Understanding Cloud-Native Architecture Cloud-native architecture is about leveraging the unique capabilities of cloud environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reclaiming Our Digital Space: The Rise of NOSTR and the Renaissance of Social Media 💪🏻</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 23:03:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</guid>
      <description>The early days of the internet were marked by a sense of freedom and innovation. Platforms like Twitter, founded by Jack Dorsey and others, were initially open-source ecosystems where developers could contribute, leading to features like hashtags and trending topics. This era was characterized by decentralized protocols, like email, allowing for diverse applications and innovation.
However, as platforms like Facebook, Twitter, and Google grew, they started organizing this vast information, turning social media into centralized repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Wearing the Same Outfit to Work Every Day - My Minimalist Journey 🌿</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-am-wearing-same-outfit-everyday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:18:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-am-wearing-same-outfit-everyday/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Minimalism is not about having less. It&amp;rsquo;s about making room for more of what matters.&amp;rdquo; - Unknown
When I first explored minimalism, I was struck by a pattern: many minimalists, myself included, often opt for a simple, repeatable outfit, such as a black t-shirt. Initially, this seemed almost like a uniform. But diving deeper into minimalism, I understood the profound reasons behind this choice.
🕵️‍♂️ Understanding Minimalism: Minimalism is more than a fashion statement; it&amp;rsquo;s a mindset that encourages us to find beauty and satisfaction in simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Productivity System: Get Things Done Effortlessly! 🚀</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:59:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</guid>
      <description>In the high-speed hustle of modern professional life, we often find ourselves chasing time, trying to grasp every fleeting minute. Productivity isn&amp;rsquo;t just a buzzword; it&amp;rsquo;s a lifeline that keeps us afloat in a sea of deadlines, meetings, and endless tasks. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a busy professional always on the lookout for the best way to streamline your day, you know that most productivity systems seem to add more to our plates rather than taking off the load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push your team to be Good to Great: Integration of Zoho Desk and Grafana</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 17:40:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/integration-of-zoho-desk-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been a part of a hardworking team that, despite their efforts, ends up shouldering blame? If yes, our situation in operations might resonate with you. On any given day, our Zoho Desk is inundated with approximately 300 tickets, each falling under various classifications and priorities. Many of these tickets are complex and time-consuming to resolve, causing them to carry over to the next day and become overdue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
