<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Book of Daniel</title>
    <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Book of Daniel</description>
    <image>
      <title>Book of Daniel</title>
      <url>https://bookofdaniel.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.134.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 08:55:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bookofdaniel.in/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Passed the CKS Exam After the October Revamp</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-passed-the-cks-exam-after-the-october-revamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 08:55:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-passed-the-cks-exam-after-the-october-revamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earning the &lt;strong&gt;Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist (CKS)&lt;/strong&gt; was the next big goal on my Kubernetes journey after clearing &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CKA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CKAD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; back in October. Riding high on the success of those certifications, I felt confident and scheduled the CKS for November. Little did I realize that this exam would challenge not just my Kubernetes skills but also my consistency and mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But thanks be to God!
He gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passing CKAD After Your CKA</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 05:57:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of Reddit users say that CKAD is easier than CKA. Personally, I agree—it does feel lighter if you attempt CKAD after completing CKA. The CKAD focuses more on scheduling tasks, while CKA involves administration of clusters. So, in CKAD, it&amp;rsquo;s more about speed and being quick with your typing to finish all the questions in time. 🏃‍♂️🕒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-study-approach&#34;&gt;My Study Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/&#34;&gt;After passing the CKA two weeks earlier&lt;/a&gt;, I had a pretty good idea of what the exam interface and questions would be like. I compared the CKA and CKAD certifications to see what additional topics I needed to cover for CKAD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How My 15-Month-Old Baby Helped Me Pass the CKA Exam</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 16:25:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last November, I scheduled my CKA exam, but guess what? I kept putting it off for months. Every time I thought about studying Kubernetes, it felt like I was facing an enormous mountain I wasn’t ready to climb. Life got busy, I lost motivation, and the exam remained on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July, I bought the KodeKloud CKA course, thinking it would push me to start studying. I studied a little, then stopped, and this cycle went on for weeks. Kubernetes seemed too big and complex to handle, and I didn’t know where to begin. And then, life happened—my father was hospitalized, and I had even less drive to study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Am Wearing Same Outfit Everyday</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-am-wearing-same-outfit-everyday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:07:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-am-wearing-same-outfit-everyday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Minimalism is not about having less. It&amp;rsquo;s about making room for more of what matters.&amp;rdquo; - Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first explored minimalism, I was struck by a pattern: many minimalists, myself included, often opt for a simple, repeatable outfit, such as a black t-shirt. Initially, this seemed almost like a uniform. But diving deeper into minimalism, I understood the profound reasons behind this choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-understanding-minimalism&#34;&gt;🕵️‍♂️ Understanding Minimalism:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is more than a fashion statement; it&amp;rsquo;s a mindset that encourages us to find beauty and satisfaction in simplicity. It&amp;rsquo;s about stripping away the non-essential to make room for what truly adds value to our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unstoppable Framework: A Step-by-Step Guide to Achieving Your Goals</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:06:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-unstoppable-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all aspire to be better, stronger, smarter, and healthier, yet many struggle to stick with their goals. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a practical framework that addresses this common issue, allowing you to effortlessly surpass your goals. This system has been successfully used to develop the discipline needed to hold a 15-minute plank every day. Join me on this journey, and let&amp;rsquo;s unlock your raw power together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-action-oriented-goals&#34;&gt;Step 1: Action-Oriented Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of setting vague and impractical goals, focus on specific actions within a defined time frame. For instance, rather than aiming to lose 20 pounds, set a goal to complete 10,000 push-ups by the end of the year. Break down the goal into actionable steps, visualize each step, and establish a non-negotiable daily minimum to make progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Productivity System: Get Things Done Effortlessly! 🚀</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:02:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-ultimate-productive-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the high-speed hustle of modern professional life, we often find ourselves chasing time, trying to grasp every fleeting minute. Productivity isn&amp;rsquo;t just a buzzword; it&amp;rsquo;s a lifeline that keeps us afloat in a sea of deadlines, meetings, and endless tasks. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, a busy professional always on the lookout for the best way to streamline your day, you know that most productivity systems seem to add more to our plates rather than taking off the load.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reclaiming Our Digital Space: The Rise of NOSTR and the Renaissance of Social Media 💪🏻</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:00:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-rise-of-nostr-and-the-renaissance-of-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The early days of the internet were marked by a sense of freedom and innovation. Platforms like Twitter, founded by Jack Dorsey and others, were initially open-source ecosystems where developers could contribute, leading to features like hashtags and trending topics. This era was characterized by decentralized protocols, like email, allowing for diverse applications and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as platforms like Facebook, Twitter, and Google grew, they started organizing this vast information, turning social media into centralized repositories. This shift was efficient but led to the accumulation of power in the hands of a few companies, creating &amp;lsquo;walled gardens&amp;rsquo; where user data became a commodity for advertising revenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Minute Death Journal Method</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-5-minute-death-journal-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:57:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/the-5-minute-death-journal-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the hustle and bustle of our daily lives, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to let moments slip by without much thought. The idea of journaling, while appealing in theory, often feels daunting in practice. After a long day, the last thing many of us want to do is reflect on our experiences and plan for the next. But what if I told you there&amp;rsquo;s a way to reap the benefits of journaling in just five minutes a day? Enter the 5-Minute Death Journal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Your Bed Summary</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/make-your-bed-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:55:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/make-your-bed-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture it: your bed, a chaotic landscape of tangled limbs and rogue pillows, mirroring the state of your life. Enter &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_H._McRaven&#34;&gt;Admiral William McRaven&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Make-Your-Bed-William-McRaven/dp/0718188861&#34;&gt;Make Your Bed&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; a book that&amp;rsquo;s anything but your average fluff-and-fold self-help manual. Think less feng shui, more forging a battle cry in the crucible of Navy SEAL training. This ain&amp;rsquo;t about smoothing out your duvet; it&amp;rsquo;s about scaling metaphorical Mount Everest, one messy pillowcase at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned From a Former WhatsApp Engineer</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:54:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/lessons-learned-from-a-former-whatsapp-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent YouTube video, a former WhatsApp engineer shared his insights on success in the tech industry and the key lessons he learned during his time at the company. Here are the main takeaways from his experience, formatted with lists and paragraphs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Key Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence and Likability&lt;/strong&gt;: Influence in the tech industry is about being likable and credible. People who are dependable and pleasant to work with are more likely to be sought after for new opportunities and promotions. Focus on building a strong reputation by being a good team player and delivering results. 👍&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Supercharge Your Focus a Revolutionary Approach</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-supercharge-your-focus-a-revolutionar-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:45:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-to-supercharge-your-focus-a-revolutionar-approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow knowledge seekers! 🚀 Recently, I stumbled upon an incredibly inspiring YouTube video that reshaped my entire approach to focus and productivity. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll distill the essence of this video into a cool, easily digestible guide. Trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s not your typical &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo; list; it&amp;rsquo;s a game-changer! (P.S. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Pe-iBysIb7o&#34;&gt;original video&lt;/a&gt; here for the full experience!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-create-your-sacred-space-&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Create Your Sacred Space&lt;/strong&gt; 🌌&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to designate a &amp;ldquo;Sacred Space&amp;rdquo; - a special area used solely for studying or working. Imagine it as a holy box where productivity reigns supreme. Once you enter this space, work begins - no exceptions! This approach mirrors insomnia research, teaching you to associate certain places with specific activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Started a YouTube Channel and Got 100K Subscribers in 6 Months (Even Though I Got Copyright Strikes)</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:35:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-started-a-youtube-channel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 lockdown, people had differing views: some felt it could be the end, while others saw it as an opportunity to start something new. One common thread was that everyone was glued to their smartphones. YouTube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/trends/articles/covid-impact/&#34;&gt;trends during the pandemic&lt;/a&gt; showed skyrocketing watch times since everyone was either watching videos or sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube Shorts started gaining more traction over time, particularly those related to motivation. Everyone needed motivation because those were the tough times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Ways to Stay Fit While Sitting at Home</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/15-ways-to-stay-fit-while-sitting-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:17:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/15-ways-to-stay-fit-while-sitting-at-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our current era of remote work and virtual learning, prioritizing physical and mental fitness is more crucial than ever. Luckily, there are numerous strategies you can incorporate into your daily routine without stepping outside your home. The following 15 ways, inspired by the insightful content from a YouTube video by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/FKNRNY5ji_M?si=ueCpV5g2vEtG5bjS&#34;&gt;Warikoo&lt;/a&gt;, will guide you towards a healthier and more balanced lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-fitness&#34;&gt;Basic Fitness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sit Straight&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintain a good posture while working or studying. Use a memory foam pillow or a similar support to keep your back straight and avoid slouching.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
