<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>K8s on Book of Daniel</title>
    <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/tags/k8s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in K8s on Book of Daniel</description>
    <image>
      <title>Book of Daniel</title>
      <url>https://bookofdaniel.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.134.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 08:55:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bookofdaniel.in/tags/k8s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Passed the CKS Exam After the October Revamp</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-passed-the-cks-exam-after-the-october-revamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 08:55:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-i-passed-the-cks-exam-after-the-october-revamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earning the &lt;strong&gt;Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist (CKS)&lt;/strong&gt; was the next big goal on my Kubernetes journey after clearing &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CKA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CKAD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; back in October. Riding high on the success of those certifications, I felt confident and scheduled the CKS for November. Little did I realize that this exam would challenge not just my Kubernetes skills but also my consistency and mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lazy-start&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lazy Start&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, my preparation was half-hearted. I had plenty of time after scheduling the exam, so I procrastinated. Days turned into weeks, and November started slipping by. Occasionally, I’d sit down to study, but I wasn’t consistent. Somewhere deep down, I knew I wasn’t preparing well enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passing CKAD After Your CKA</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 05:57:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/passing-ckad-after-your-cka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of Reddit users say that CKAD is easier than CKA. Personally, I agree—it does feel lighter if you attempt CKAD after completing CKA. The CKAD focuses more on scheduling tasks, while CKA involves administration of clusters. So, in CKAD, it&amp;rsquo;s more about speed and being quick with your typing to finish all the questions in time. 🏃‍♂️🕒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-study-approach&#34;&gt;My Study Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/&#34;&gt;After passing the CKA two weeks earlier&lt;/a&gt;, I had a pretty good idea of what the exam interface and questions would be like. I compared the CKA and CKAD certifications to see what additional topics I needed to cover for CKAD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How My 15-Month-Old Baby Helped Me Pass the CKA Exam</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 16:25:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/how-my-15-month-old-baby-helped-me-pass-the-cka-exam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last November, I scheduled my CKA exam, but guess what? I kept putting it off for months. Every time I thought about studying Kubernetes, it felt like I was facing an enormous mountain I wasn’t ready to climb. Life got busy, I lost motivation, and the exam remained on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July, I bought the KodeKloud CKA course, thinking it would push me to start studying. I studied a little, then stopped, and this cycle went on for weeks. Kubernetes seemed too big and complex to handle, and I didn’t know where to begin. And then, life happened—my father was hospitalized, and I had even less drive to study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why YAML and How to Ace It?</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-yaml-and-how-to-ace-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 21:15:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/why-yaml-and-how-to-ace-it/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered why on earth YAML was invented? I’ve been there—it can feel tough with all the indentation rules and quirks! If you’re feeling the same way, this blog post is for you!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Architecture Explained the Ship Analogy of KodeKloud</title>
      <link>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kubernetes-architecture-explained-the-ship-analogy-of-kodekloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 13:52:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bookofdaniel.in/posts/kubernetes-architecture-explained-the-ship-analogy-of-kodekloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our exploration of Kubernetes architecture! Kubernetes, often abbreviated as K8s, is a powerful tool designed to manage containerized applications in a scalable and automated fashion. This blog post aims to provide a high-level understanding of Kubernetes architecture using an analogy of ships, which simplifies the complex interplay between its components. Special thanks to KodeKloud for their insightful lecture, which inspired this overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-kubernetes-cluster-ships-at-sea&#34;&gt;The Kubernetes Cluster: Ships at Sea&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, a Kubernetes cluster comprises two types of nodes: worker nodes and master nodes. To understand their roles, let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a fleet of ships:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
